How does it work?<br/>
To calculate a specific property of your rocket, you will have to check one of the 4 boxes in the panel on the left (the one with the blue containers) You can check up to two, but you cannot check Δv <em>and</em> Isp, or Thrust <em>and</em> TWR at the same time because for each pair of values, the calculation of one is dependant on the other. Once you have checked the properties you want calculated, you can type in the number of stages you want to calculate (maximum nine), or you can skip it and click the "Create Rocket" button underneath. This will display a chart where you can add or delete stages, and enter the necessary information to complete the calculation. There will also be text boxes where you cannot enter information. That's where your results will be displayed. Once you have entered the required information, click "Calculate". The chart should fill up entirely with values, but if there is an error, the calculation will not be completed, and you will get a message below telling you what went wrong. If this happens, you will have to change some of the values in the chart and try again. <br/>
<br/>
Once you have made a successful calculation, you will have the option of saving your rocket. You can only make a save if you are logged into an account. After saving your rocket, you will see an orange chart show up underneath the purple calculation chart that lists your saved rockets. You can use this chart to modify or delete the rockets you have already created, so you don't have to re-enter the information over and over again.<br/>
<br/>
Things to note:<br/>
<ul style="text-align: left">
<li>
If you calculate a chart that has empty or incomplete stages, the calculation will not work. Make sure to fill in all of the necessary text boxes for every stage.
</li>
<li>
Deleting a stage in the middle of the chart will make the stages below it collapse onto it. If you need to input new values to a stage, it is probably more frugal to delete each value individualy and then re-enter them, rather than deleting and creating entire stages.
</li>
<li>
It is perfectly safe to switch around the columns. If decide while making your list that you want to perform a different calculation, you can change the check boxes in the left panel, and the values in your chart will be hidden, but preserved. Be careful with the "Calculate" button, though, because performing a calculation may overwrite anything in the columns of the properties being calculated.
</li>
<li>
Checking the "Thrust", "min", and "max" boxes will only calculate the thrust from the min. TWR. This is because only one of these is necessary for the calculation, and performing both calculations would create ambiguity. In order to calculate the maximum required thrust, you must un-check the "min" box.
</li>
<li>
Typically, the Δv and TWR are chosen to calculate because engines already have a fixed Isp and thrust.<br/>
However, consider the following:<br/>
If you are trying to build a rocket to perform a task, such as landing on the moon (or Mun), you will require a certain TWR to land safely. By checking the "Thrust" box, you can find the minimum <em>required</em> thrust your engine will need to land. This way, you will know which engines are suitable without having to perform a TWR calculation for each one.
</li>
</ul><br/>
<br/>
Why isn't this a KSP game mod?<br/>
<br/>
Rocket Calculator could someday become a mod for Kerbal Space Program, but I made it a priority to create a tool that is new and different. Kerbal Space Program already has several great mods that perform similar functionality (such as Kerbal Engineer Redux), and as a web application, Rocket Calculator can be used by non-pc gamers and space enthusiasts who cannot access those mods without playing the game. Rocket Calculator also won't require maintanence every time a new version of the game is released.