How does it work?<br/>
To calculate a specific property of your rocket, you will have to check one of the 4 boxes in the panel on the left (the one with the blue containers) You can check up to two, but you cannot check Δv <em>and</em> Isp, or Thrust <em>and</em>TWR at the same time because the calculation of each property is dependant on the other in its pair. Once you have checked the properties you want calculated, you can type in the number of stages you want to calculate (maximum nine), or you can skip it and click the "Create Rocket" button underneath. This will display a chart where you can enter the necessary information to complete the calculation. There will also be text boxes you cannot enter information. That's where your results will be displayed. Once you have entered the required information, click "Calculate". The chart should fill up entirely with values, but if there is an error, the calculation will not be completed, and you will get a message below telling you what went wrong. If this happens, you will have to change some of the values in the chart and try again.<br/>
<br/>
Things to note:<br/>
<ul>
<li>
If your chart features more stages than you plan on calculating, you will need to delete the extra stages, or else the calculation will not work.
</li>
<li>
Deleting a stage in the middle of the chart will make the stages below it collapse onto it. If you need to input new values, it is probably more frugal to delete each value individualy and then re-enter, rather than deleting and creating new stages.
</li>
<li>
It is safe, however, to switch around the columns. If decide while making your list that you want to perform a different calculation, you can change the check boxes in the left panel, and the values in your chart will be preserved. Be careful with the "Calculate" button, though, because performing a successful calculation will overwrite anything in the columns of the properties being calculated.
</li>
<li>
Typically, the Δv and TWR are chosen to calculate because engines already have a fixed Isp and thrust.<br/>
However, consider the following:<br/>
If you are trying to build a rocket to perform a task, such as landing on the moon (or Mun), you will require a certain TWR to land safely. You can check the "Thrust" box, input the necessary Δv for the journey into the table, and calculate the minimum <em>required</em> thrust. After that, you can look through your engines and simply choose one that has at least as much thrust as the result. This certainly beats having to do separate calculations for each engine until you find one that works.
</li>
</ul>